Register of the Charles Hill Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1942-1989.
  - Literature and literary criticism
    - "Who Killed Criticism?" by Gerald Graff, American Scholar, undated
    - "A Will to Cultural Power: Deconstructing the de Man Scandal" by Mark Edmundson, Harper's, July 1988
  - Logan Act. Text, notes, memorandum, ca. 1988 (Box 16)
  - MacArthur, Douglas. Printed matter, May 1966
  - Marine Security Guard Program. Correspondence, historical background note, 1986
  - Marxism. "Dialectical Immaterialism" by Frederick Crews, American Scholar, undated; "Marxism vs. the Jews," Commentary, April 1984
  - Middle East. Statements by George Shultz, 1988; notes, memoranda, map, press reports, printed matter, 1975-1988
  - Miller, Perry
    - "Mind of Perry Miller" by Ann Douglas, New Republic, February 3, 1982
    - "Perry Miller" by Kenneth S. Lynn, American Scholar, undated
  - Miscellany
  - Mondale, Walter
    - Knesset address, July 2, 1978
    - Text of speech accepting the Presidential nomination, New York Times, July 20, 1984
  - Moral philosophy. Printed matter, 1983
  - National Security Archive. "Archival Pursuit" by William Triplett, City Paper, February 6, 1987 (Box 17)
  - National Security Council (NSC). Staff and Iran-Contra
  - Nationalism
    - "Center Holds, I and II" by Jonathan Rieder, New Republic, September 12 and 19, 1988
    - "Theories of Nationalism and Historical Explanation" by Arthur N. Waldron, World Politics, undated
    - "What Is Nationalism and Why Should We Study It?" by Ernst B. Haas, International Organization, Summer 1986
  - Neoconservatism. Printed matter, 1986
  - "New Federalist." Correspondence, memoranda, notes, drafts, printed matter, and typescript (also entitled elsewhere "Democracy and Foreign Policy"), 1951-1988
  - New York. Printed matter, undated
  - Nitze, Paul. Toast to Paul Nitze on his 80th birthday, 1987
  - Nixon, Richard
    - "Lessons of the Alger Hiss Case," New York Times, January 8, 1986
    - "In Praise of Richard Nixon" by Paul Johnson, Commentary, October 1988
    - "Mr. Nixon's Chimerical Detente" by Seymour Weiss, Wall Street Journal, June 4, 1984
    - "Nixon, Watergate, and American Foreign Policy" by Stephen W. Stathis, Presidential Studies Quarterly, undated
    - "Richard Nixon, Prophet: He's Wrong" by Andrew Sullivan, New Republic, August 29, 1988
  - North, Oliver. Memorandum from Abraham D. Sofaer, November 15, 1988; printed matter
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO). Reports, 1962
  - Norway - History. Printed matter, undated
  - Nuclear weapons. Printed matter, 1984-1989
  - Oberdorfer, Don. Chronology for proposed book; articles from Washington Post, 1983-1988
  - Oil. "Anglo-American Oil Agreement and the Wartime Search for Foreign Oil Policy" by Michael B. Stoff, Business History Review, Spring 1981
  - Pacific Rim. "Myth or Reality of the Pacific Century" by Christopher Coker, Washington Quarterly, Summer 1988 (Box 18)
  - Pacifism. Printed matter, 1988
  - Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO). Memorandum, December 20, 1988
  - Panama. Press conference by George Shultz, Michael Armacost, and Elliott Abrams, May 25, 1988; summary of General Manuel Noriega's views on psychological warfare; printed matter
  - People's Temple, Georgetown, Guyana. "Performance of the Department of State and the American Embassy in Georgetown, Guyana in the People's Temple Case,", 1979
  - Philippines. Correspondence; chronology of Philippines history, 1983-1988; printed matter, 1988-1989
  - Philosophy
    - "Coming Out Into the Corridor: Postmodern Fantasies of Pluralism" by Carl Rapp, Georgia Review, undated
    - "Dropping the Object" by Anthony Quinton, Partisan Review, undated
    - "Ernst Bloch: Philosopher of 'Hope'" by J. P. Stern, undated
    - "George Santayana and the Consolations of Philosophy" by Joseph Epstein, New Criterion, June 1987
    - "Hermes, Clio, Themis: Historical Interpretation and Legal Hermeneutics" by Donald Kelley, undated
    - "Looking After Virtue" by Roger Kimball, New Criterion, September 1988
    - "Never Speculate, Never Explain: The State of Contemporary Philosophy" by Kenneth R. Seskin, American Scholar, undated
    - "New Directions in Modern Thought" by Daniel Bell and others, Partisan Review, undated
    - "Posties" by Richard Rorty, London Review of Books, September 3, 1987
    - "Recovery of Practical Philosophy" by Stephen Toulmin, American Scholar, undated
  - Plato
    - "A Lecture on Plato's Apology" by James Redfield, Journal of General Education, undated
    - "Translating Plato: Some Reflections on Rhetoric" by John Bremer, World and I, July 1987
  - Poetry. Printed matter, 1973-1988
  - Politics and government
    - "Dateline Washington: The Rules of the Games" by Stanley J. Heginbotham, Foreign Policy, undated
    - "A Dream of Change," Times Literary Supplement, January 13-19, 1989
    - "Fundamental Concepts of A Study of History: Withdrawal and Return - The Examples of Muhammed and Machiavelli,", undated
    - "Making of Modern Times," Harper's, undated
    - "'New Science of Politics' and the Old Art of Governing" by Daniel Patrick Moynihan, the Britannia Lecture, Smithsonian Institution, September 1986
    - "Politics and the Devil" by Leszek Kolakowski, Men and Ideas, undated
    - "President and the Secretary of State" by Theodore C. Sorensen, Foreign Affairs, undated
    - "Rediscovering Complexity" by Benjamin DeMott, Atlantic Monthly, September 1988
    - "Republican Revisionism Revisited" by Isaac Kramnick, 1979-80
    - "Rethinking Liberalism: The Politics of Post Industrialism," a course syllabus, undated
    - "Toward a New Fusionism?" by Paul Gottfried, Policy Review, Fall 1987
  - Polygraph tests. Memorandum, parliamentary question and answer, December 14, 1988
  - Population. "Staying Alive: Some Home Truths About Population" by W. Petersen, American Scholar, undated
  - Pound, Ezra. Printed matter, 1985
  - Presidency
    - "Executive Presidency: Federal Management for the 1990's," a Report by an Academy Panel for the 1988-89 Presidential Transition, September 1988
    - Presentation to the Office of Management and Budget Staff by Paul H. O'Neill, September 6, 1988
    - "A Republic of Souls: Puritanism and the American Presidency" by Richard Sennett, Harper's, undated
    - "Sources of Presidential Power: John Adams and the Challenge to Executive Primacy" by Jean S. Holder, Political Science Quarterly, 1986
    - "Tales From the Top: Inside the White House with Eight Former Presidential Aides," Washington Monthly, April 1987
    - "War Powers of the President: How Flexible? How Limited?" by Robert F. Turner, remarks at the Perspectives on Public Policy Conference, Brookings Institution, December 2, 1984
    - "Without Portfolio" by Bernard Gwertzman, undated
  - Presidents – United States - Election
    - 1984
    - 1988
  - Press leaks.
    See Gelb, Leslie, and Leaking
  - Private property. Note, outline, undated
  - Protocol. Memorandum from Selwa Roosevelt, reviewing her tenure as Chief of Protocol, December 16, 1988
  - Psychoanalysis
    - "Analytic Triangle" by David James Fisher, Partisan Review, undated
    - "Reflections" by Janet Malcolm, New Yorker, April 20, 1987
  - Quinn, Kenneth. Letter to Alan Romberg from Mary McGrory, 1978; commencement address, May 20, 1984 (Box 19)
  - Quotations. Miscellaneous quotations
  - Racism. "A 'New Racism' on Campus?" by Thomas Short, Commentary, August 1988
  - Reagan, Ronald and the Reagan Presidency. Printed matter, 1982-1989; handwritten note on a note from Mikhail Gorbachev, February 4, 1987
  - Refugees. Memorandum on refugees from the Soviet Union, November 3, 1988
  - Religion. Printed matter, 1986-1988
  - Rinpoche (Chogyam Trungpa).
    Notes, printed matter
  - Said, Edward W. "Secular Criticism," Raritan, 1983; "Conspiracy of Praise," Nation, October 19, 1985
  - School busing. Flyer from Bridgeton, New Jersey, undated
  - Secretary of State Library.
    See United States.
    Department of State/List of holdings
  - Shultz, George P. (Box 20)
    - Biographical information
    - Clippings, including printed matter on the Shultz/Weinberger debate, and "Ethics and American Power," ed. by E. Lefever, May 1985
    - Memoranda
    - Speeches
      - Address to the United Nations, undated
      - "Democracy and Foreign Policy,", undated
      - "U.S. Foreign Policy: Realism and Progress," U.N. General Assembly, September 30, 1982
      - "Human Rights and the Moral Dimension of U.S. Foreign Policy,", January 27, 1984
      - Remarks, Wellington, New Zealand, July 16, 1984
      - "Power and Diplomacy," Veterans of Foreign Wars, August 20, 1984
      - Remarks, Yeshiva Univ., November 16, 1984
      - Remarks, National Prayer Breakfast, January 31, 1985
      - "Meaning of Vietnam," Department of State, April 25, 1985
      - Address at Yad Vashem, Israel, May 10, 1985
      - Remarks, Canberra, Australia, July 1985
      - Remarks, PEN International Conference, January 10, 1986
      - "Terrorism and the Summit Partners," statement, May 5, 1986
        (draft)
      - "Protectionism and Foreign Policy: America in the Third Wave of Expansion," Economic Club of New York, June 10, 1986
      - Remarks, Northwestern Univ., June 14, 1986
      - Remarks, Society for Historians of American Foreign Relations, June 25, 1986
      - "Reykjavik: Where Do We Go From Here?" National Press Club, October 17, 1986
      - Remarks, U.S. Senate Youth, February 5, 1987
      - Toast to Prime Minister of Italy, Giovanni Goria, December 17, 1987
      - Remarks, Conference of Presidents of Major American Jewish Organizations, February 28, 1988
      - "U.S. Policy in the Middle East," Department of State, June 1988
      - "Knowledge and Power,", June 15, 1988
      - Remarks, National Foreign Policy Conference for Educators, June 24, 1988
      - Remarks, Committee on Foreign Relations breakfast, July 21, 1988
      - "Administration's Approach to Middle East Peacemaking," Washington Institute for Near East Policy, September 16, 1988
      - "Ecology of International Change,", October 25, 1988
        (unused draft)
      - Remarks, Institute for the Study of Diplomacy reception, November 16, 1988
      - Interview, Worldnet, November 30, 1988
      - Statement about James Baker, III, 1989
    - Travel
  - Sisco, Joe. Aide-memoire on Israel, undated (Box 21)
  - Smith, Henry Nash. "American Studies of Henry Nash Smith," by Richard Bridgman, American Scholar, undated
  - Social science. "Blurred Genres: The Refiguration of Social Thought" by Clifford Geertz, American Scholar, undated
  - Socrates. Book introduction, undated; bibliography
  - Sofaer, Abraham
    - Correspondence
    - Speeches and writings
      - "International Law and the Use of Force," National Interest, Fall 1988
      - "Law and Terrorism," Columbia University School of Law, April 5, 1986
  - Sontag, Susan. Reviews, undated
  - Southern Africa. Printed matter, including "Sanctions '86: How the State Department Prevailed" by Constantine C. Menges, National Interest, Fall 1988
  - Soviet Union – Foreign relations – Great Britain.
  - Speech writing and speeches. Notes, 1988; printed matter, 1982-1985
  - Stanford University
    - General
    - Institute of International Studies (IIS)
  - Steiner, George. New Republic, November 19, 1984
  - Stern, Isaac. Tribute to George Shultz (remarks in honor of Roger Stevens), Kennedy Center, December 3, 1988
  - Stolar, Abe. "Bitter Pilgrimage of Abe Stolar" by David Remnick, Washington Post, May 10, 1988
  - Strauss, Leo. Printed matter, including "Legacy of Leo Strauss" by D. D'Souza, Policy Review, Spring 1987
  - Student dissent. "Our Towns: The Yale Strike and the Causes of the 60's" by Michael Norman, New York Times, November 1, 1984
  - Syria. "A U.S. 'Syrian Strategy',", October 12, 1983
  - Tau, Malineo. "Goodbye, Mrs. Tau, You Made a Difference" by Sanford J. Ungar, Washington Post, July 28, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Terrorism. Printed matter, 1984-1986
  - Thatcher, Margaret. Quotations, review of books about Mrs. Thatcher, New Republic, November 7, 1988
  - Thoreau, Henry D. Review of books about Thoreau, Times Literary Supplement, October 6, 1978
  - Thucydides. "Democracy and Distrust: A Lesson from Thucydides" by Clifford Orwin, American Scholar, undated
  - Totalitarianism. Printed matter, 1986
  - Trade policy. Letter from George Shultz to Ronald Reagan, May 4, 1988, with enclosure of "Trade Powers Act," Wall Street Journal
  - Turkey. Correspondence; printed matter, 1970-1987; "Turkey, Great Britain, and Sinai" by W.White, 1973
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (U.S.S.R.). Memorandum, "Soviet Union and the Problem of Conflict Resolution" by Vladimir A. Lefebvre, 1984; printed matter, 1965-1988; maps
  - United Nations. Notes, draft, reports, 1962
  - United States
    - Economic conditions. Memoranda, printed matter, 1988
    - Foreign economic policy. Printed matter, 1972-1984
    - Foreign relations
      - General, 1978-1988
        - Memoranda
        - Printed matter
      - Catholic Church. Printed matter, ca. 1984 (Box 23)
      - Cuba. Printed matter, 1987
      - Europe. Printed matter, 1983
      - Japan. Printed matter, 1985-1987
      - Middle East. Printed matter (article on Harold Saunders), ca. 1975
      - Soviet Union. Reports, 1985-1988; printed matter, 1984-1988
      - Vatican.
        See Catholic Church
    - History. Printed matter, 1988
  - United States. Congress. Printed matter, 1988
  - United States. Department of State.
    - Charts.
      See also Oversize File
    - Correspondence
    - List of holdings of the Secretary of State Library and note by Charles Hill, undated
    - Memoranda
    - Notes
    - Personnel information (Box 24)
    - Printed matter, including GIST, "Samizdat" (parody of Department of State newsletter), catalogs about the Diplomatic Reception Rooms, and miscellaneous clippings, 1969-1989
    - Reports, including "Organizational History of the Department of State Since 1960,", 1984
  - United States. Embassy (Soviet Union). Printed matter, 1988
  - United States. Library of Congress. Remarks by James H. Billington, Librarian of Congress, National Press Club, January 1989; printed matter, undated
  - University of Chicago. Printed matter, 1985-1987.
  - Vessey, John W., Jr. Remarks at National Prayer Breakfast, February 3, 1983
  - Vietnam. Outline for book; copy of letter from Le Duan, undated; printed matter, 1973-1988 (Box 25)
  - War
    - Memorandum
    - "Causes of Wars" by Michael Howard, Wilson Quarterly, Summer 1984
    - "Constraints on America's Conduct of Small Wars," International Security, Fall 1984
    - "Defining Military Character" by Philip Lewis, Karl Kuhnert, and Robert Maginnis, Parameters, Summer 1987
    - "Deterrence or National Interest?" by David E. Kaiser, Forum, Spring 1986
    - "Eternal Clausewitz" by Martin van Creveld, Clausewitz and Modern Strategy, undated
    - "Illusion of Limited War: Chancellor Bethmann Hollweg's Calculated Risk, July 1914" by Konrad H. Jarausch, undated
    - "Just War and Matters of Statecraft" by James Finn, Washington Quarterly, Summer 1988
    - "Space and Time in On War" by Harold W. Nelson, Clausewitz and Modern Strategy, undated
    - "Uses and Abuses of Clausewitz" by Eric Alterman, Parameters, Summer 1987
  - War Powers Resolution. Memoranda, 1984, 1988; testimony of Abraham Sofaer, 1988; printed matter, undated
  - Western civilization. Printed matter, undated
  - Wilder, Thornton. "Remembering Thornton Wilder" by Elder Olson, American Scholar, undated
  - Wills, Garry. Review of Inventing America, 1978
  - Wilson, Woodrow
    - "Submarine and American Intervention" by Charles Seymour, undated
    - "Submarine Thesis Challenged" by H.E. Barnes, undated
    - "Woodrow Wilson and the Russian Revolution" by Betty Miller Unterberger, undated
    - "Woodrow Wilson's Neurological Illness" by Edwin A. Weinstein, Journal of American History, September 1970
  - Wolfson, Harry A. "On the Sleuth of Slobodka and the Cortez of Kabbalah" by Judah Goldin, review of Wolfson of Harvard by Leo W. Schwarz in American Scholar, undated
  - World War, 1914-1918.
    Notes, undated
  - Wriston, Walter. Speech at the International Monetary Conference, June 4, 1984
  - Writing. Printed matter, 1986-1988
- Oversize File, undated. (Box 26)
  See also oversize materials in the Stanford Years File (Box 39)
  Certificate of appreciation, Chinese army cap, memorabilia, maps, notebooks of pins, organizational charts.
  - Maps
  - Mao Tse-tung pins.
    Two notebooks
  - Chinese Army cap
  - Organization charts, Department of State, 1984, 1990
  - Certificate of appreciation from Ronald Reagan for participation in Toronto Summit, June 19-21, 1988
- Card File, undated. (Box 27-29)
  Includes holograph and typewritten notes on the Cultural Revolution in China, 1967-1968
- Stanford Years File, 1989-1992. (Box 31)
  Correspondence, speeches and writings (mostly by others but also by Charles Hill), course notes, subject files related to Charles Hill's work as Diplomat-in-Residence at Stanford University and as Senior Research Fellow at the Hoover Institution, as well as at the United Nations, arranged alphabetically by physical form. The subject file also includes writings by Charles Hill. Includes some earlier material
  - Biographical file
    - General
    - Articles, clippings, 1987-1992
    - Awards
    - Charles Hill Papers.
      Deposit agreement with the Hoover Institution
    - George Shultz Papers in the Federal Records Center, San Bruno, California. Regulations for access
    - Honorary doctorate - Glassboro State, May 19, 1989
    - Miscellany
  - Career file
    - General
      - General
      - Course material, talks, seminars
      - Performance record, April 1986 - April 1987
      - Reference letter from Nicholas Platt, November 1989
      - Resumes
      - Vouchers
    - Diplomat-in-Residence. Briefing book
    - Foreign service
    - Research and writing. Plans, charts, outlines, correspondence
    - Retirement
      - General - Tax information
      - Department of State
    - Senior Research Fellow, Hoover Institution
    - Travel (Box 32)
      - 1979-1987
      - 1988 (Box 33)
    - Travel and moving, 1988-1989
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1987-1990
    - Baker, James, III (Charles Hill's letter of resignation), 1989
    - Baldwin, George and Harriet, 1989
    - Barker, Richard, 1990
    - Barkley, Richard, 1990
    - Barnett, Robert, 1989
    - Bavly, Dan, 1988-1989
    - Bender, Boni, 1989
    - Bergold, Harry, 1987
    - Boeker, Paul (Institute of the Americas), 1989
    - Bolton, Peter, 1988
    - Brinker, William, 1991
    - Camp, John McKay, 1987 (?)
    - Carnochan, Bliss and Gitta, 1989-1990
    - Castle, Peter and Ellen, 1977
    - Cates, Arthur, 1984
    - Creagan, David, 1989-1990
    - Crocker, Chester, 1989
    - Dam, Kenneth, 1988
    - Ditz, John, 1990 (Box 34)
    - Drachkovitch, Milorad, 1990
    - Edelman, Eric, 1989
    - Farrell, Tom, 1987
    - Feldman, Shai, 1988
    - Fincher, John, 1987-1988
    - Fisher, Max, 1988
    - Freelen, Bob, 1990
    - Gaston, Elizabeth, 1989-1990
    - Griswold, Charles L., Jr., 1989-1990
    - Grossman, Danny, 1990
    - Gubitz, Myron, 1990
    - Henriksen, Thomas, 1989-1990
    - Henry, Rodney, 1990
    - Hill, Emily, 1988
    - James, Herman D., 1989
    - Johnson, Lionel, 1989
    - Karnow, Stanley, 1989
    - Kennedy-Minott, Rodney, 1990
    - Kirby, William, 1990
    - Kurtzer, Dan, 1990
    - LaFeber, Walter, 1985-1989
    - Levy, Arnold, 1988-1989
    - Mathews, Jay, 1989
    - Mayor, Maya, 1989
    - McFarlane, Robert, 1986
    - Mergen, Bernard, 1988-1990
    - Middlebrook, Diane, 1989
    - Mnookin, Robert, 1990
    - Morton, Elaine, 1989
    - Nader, George, 1990
    - National Interest, 1990
    - Nee, Victor, 1990
    - Perkins, Edward, 1989
    - Peterson, Agnes, 1990
    - Randle, Wilma, 1989-1990
    - Rydzkowski, Janusz, 1990
    - Seitz, R. G. H., 1988
    - Sheldon, Walter, 1990
    - Shultz, George, 1989
    - Sicherman, Harvey, 1988-1990
    - Sofaer, Abraham, 1989-1990
    - Stanford University Press, 1990
    - Sullivan, Brendan, 1988
    - Thompson, William M., Jr., 1989
    - Vest, George, 1988-1989
    - Vogel, Ezra, 1989
    - Waldron, Arthur, 1990
    - Walsh, Lawrence E., 1990
    - Williams, William Appleman, 1985
    - Williamson, Larry, 1989
    - Wong, Marcia, 1988-1989
  - Speeches and writings (Box 35)
    - General
      - Letter to the editor, Nation, January 1976, in reply to Alexander Woodside
      - Memoranda and marginalia by Charles Hill on Robert McFarlane, September 30, 1983
      - Draft outline on foreign policy, February 13, 1985
      - Outline by George Shultz to Ronald Reagan on the Iran-Contra Affair, July 28, 1987
    - 1989
      - "Statecraft," handwritten draft, February
      - Cornell University Lectures, Clark Fellow, April 19-20
      - Stanford World Institute: A Prospectus, May
      - Introduction of Al Vecchione, May 30
      - James Baker proposal for a "Pan-Pacific Alliance,", June 28
      - "How to Better Govern in the Face of Difficult Situations," History Book Club, July
      - "Memoir" by George Shultz, July
      - Television taping outline on Lewis and Clark, July
      - "Statecraft" with handwritten notes by Henry Kissinger, July 20
      - "Five+ Year Diplomatic Effort to Restore Stability in the Middle East," handwritten outline, August 14
      - "Statecraft" outline, September 12
      - Notes by Charles Hill on U.S. policy and the Middle East peace process, Washington Institute for Near East Policy, Wye Plantation, September 15-17
      - "Jerusalem,", October
      - "Reflections on Drug Policy,", October 11
      - "On Governance,", October 11
      - Letter to the editor, Newsweek, November 3
      - Cambridge University, draft, November 4
    - 1990
      - "Hoover Institution in the 1990s: The International Dimension,", January 5
      - Poem for George Shultz on not being Secretary of State any longer, January 19
      - "Dealing With the Next Danger of War," with Edward Teller, January 29
      - "Imperative of Realism in the Middle East,", February 14
      - "Sovereignty and Nationalism in the Information Age," Glassboro State College, February 15
      - Letter to the editor, Stanford Daily, February 26
      - "Neglected Dimension of the Middle East Conflict,", March 2
      - "United States and Europe,", March 21
      - "Man Thinking," American Studies International, April (Box 36)
      - "Lithuanian Pivot,", April
      - "Ignoring Lithuania's Cries," San Jose Mercury News, April 15
      - Conference on the Transformation of Europe, Options Paper, April 19
      - Polish Foreign Service Program with Hoover/Stanford, draft, May 1
      - "Summit Fatigue,", May 8
      - "Bush-Gorbachev Summit May Be Last Of Its Kind," San Francisco Chronicle, May 15
      - Roh Tae Woo-Gorbachev meeting, May 31
      - Presentation of poster to Mikhail Gorbachev, Stanford University, June 5
      - "Confirmation" (Senate confirmation for appointed positions), June 5
      - Coro Foundation. Information, June 6
      - "How the State Department Works,", June 6
      - "Diplomacy Versus Terrorism,", June 11
      - Notes by Charles Hill, Washington Institute on Middle East Policy, June 29
      - Printed matter and Charles Hill's memo to Lawrence Eagleburger on Cambodia, July
      - "Clusters," to John Raisian, July 10
      - Middle East, August 17
      - "Science, Technology, and Post Modernity,", September 1
      - "American Republican Movement - Enlightenment or Deconstruction,", September 2
      - U.S.-China Relations, September 6
      - Notes on Philip Habib, September 6
      - "Gulf Crisis: War or Peace in the Middle East,", September 14-16